

# Front End Developer

<u>alexhannan.com</u> <u>github/alexjhannan</u> <u>linkedin/alexjhannan</u>

alexjhannan@gmail.com

Brooklyn, NY

(856) 296-2569

# SUMMARY

Versatile, self-taught developer with close to two years of experience working on React applications. Excellent communicator with a track record of bringing great designs to life. Former STEM educator with a B.S. in Physics and a lifelong passion for technology.

### **EXPERIENCE**

Software Engineer @ Codecademy New York City, NY - Aug 2017 - Mar 2018

- Developed conversion and engagement features in a React/Rails environment
- Member of a cross-functional team focused on creating and maintaining user value
- Drove a 14% increase in multi-month subscriptions by adding a six month option
- Visually refreshed Catalog and Dashboard content with reusable card components
- Synced with the design team to iterate front end tools toward a design system
- Created on-platform ads to sustainably route users to the company's paid offerings

Software Engineer @ Teachers Pay Teachers New York City, NY - Oct 2016 - May 2017

- Aided React platform expansion during a site migration from PHP to React/Node
- Established front end standards by reaching consensus on best practices
- Implemented Storybook as a component explorer and documentation hub
- Documented coding patterns for component-driven development (CDD)
- Advocated for CDD, which yielded a cross-functional boost in efficiency

Software Engineer @ Neosavvy New York City, NY - Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

- Developed quick-start seed applications for React, Angular 2, and Webpack
- Stabilized code using testing harnesses with Mocha/Chai, Jasmine, and AVA
- Trained in Haskell for exposure to functional programming concepts

# **EDUCATION**

B.S. Physics, Temple University Philadelphia, PA (GPA 3.83) — Jan 2014

- Multiple honors, member of several honors fraternities (math, physics, PBK)
- Applied programming fundamentals for experimentation and simulation

### TECHNICAL FOCUS

- React, Redux, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Webpack, Git, Unit Testing, Prototyping
- Adept with various backend technologies, including Rails and Node/Express
- Interested in leveling-up team process with shared language and systems